有人在追我
I've got one on my tail.
我们甩掉了追我们的人
We lost ours.
我们得止血  走吧
We need to take care of that bleeding. Let's go.
这边
This way.
好  现在怎么办
Okay. What now?
等到日出  杀光他们
Wait 'til dawn, hunt them down.
或者我们可以带食物走
Or we just get the food and go.
手上捧着一堆食物离开这里吗
And what? Walk out of here with our arms full?
只要能离开这里就行
As long as we walk out of here, yeah.
除非我们来这里不只是为了食物
Unless chow ain't the only thing we're here for.
我不会丢下达里尔和加百利
I'm not leaving Daryl and Gabriel.
我也不会冒险被跟踪回家
And I won't risk being followed home.
卡弗  报告
Carver, report.
我在医务室
In the infirmary.
那个领袖甩掉了我  但我会找到她的
The leader slipped me, but I'll get her.
快找到她
Just find her.
不能放他们任何一个活着回去
Not one of them's getting out of here alive.
收到
Copy that.
行尸走肉
第十一季  第九集
找不到朱迪思和格雷西
Hey -- we can't find Judith and Gracie.
她们没上楼
They never made it up.
好  你加入我们
Okay. You're with us.
我们杀过去找她们
We get through this and we find them.
撑不住了
It's not gonna hold.
撑得住
It will.
来吧
Come on.
我来
I've got it.
还能用什么东西
What else can we use?
雨没用
Rain's not helping.
风把火越吹越旺
The wind just keeps stoking the flames.
抱歉  老大  但里面太热了
Sorry, boss, but it's scorching in there.
要不放弃吧
Might be time to call it off.
不
No.
试试别的方法
Just gotta try something else.
比如找辆救火车
Like a firetruck.
过来  快
Come here! Come on!
快
Come on!
缺口怎么样
The breach?
大门旁边的那个封上了
We closed the one by the gate.
很好  现在想办法灭火吧
Good, now let's focus on the flames.
等等  墙内行尸太多了
Hang on. There's too many sickos inside the walls.
肯定还有别的缺口
There's gotta be another breach.
斯科特和其他人在检查死胡同
Scott and the others are checking the cul-de-sac,
我们打算去东墙看看
and we're headed toward the east wall.
假如风车倒了
If this windmill falls,
会砸出一个无法修补的大口
it could create an opening too big to close.
我去找缺口
我和你一起去
I'll go with you.
我们找缺口  你们处理风车  好吗
We find the breach, and you take care of the windmill, okay?
好
Okay.
当心点
你也是
什么声音
What's that?
格雷西  那是紧急信号
Gracie. That's our emergency signal.
把火灭了  不然我们会失去一切
Put out that fire or we could lose everything.
快去
Go!
为了教皇
For Pope.
奥斯汀  你在里面吗
Austin, you in there?
奥斯汀
Austin?
砸开
Break it down.
不不不
No, no, no.
见鬼
Shit.
够了
No more.
我们得去窗户那里
We need to get to the window.
如果能够到管道...
If we could reach this pipe...
太高了
It's too high!
不
No!
格雷西  朱迪思
Gracie! Judith!
格雷西
Gracie!
-撑住  -爸爸
- Hang on! - Daddy!
爸
Dad!
留在原地  留在原地
Stay there! Stay there!
过来  过来
Come on! Come on!
过来
Come on!
去窗户那边
Go to the window!
窗户
The window.
爸  你没事吧
Dad, you okay?
你呢
Are you?
还有行尸
There's more!
好  上去
Okay. Up you go.
来吧
Come on.
快点  朱迪思
Come on, Judith.
-你们走  -你呢
- You go ahead! - What about you?
-我去叫人  -快走  先带格雷西去避险
- I'll get help --Go! Get Gracie to safety first!
我没问题的
I've got this!
屋顶入口
够近了
That's far enough.
我不能让你伤害我的信众
I can't let you harm one of my flock.
先担心你自己吧
Worry about yourself first.
上帝会阻止你的
God will stay your hand.
就像祂昨天在墓地做的那样
Just like he did at the graves yesterday.
-你知道我在那里  -上帝知道
- You knew I was there? - The Lord did.
祂说我不用害怕
He told me I had nothing to fear.
-你能听见祂说话  -是的
- You hear him? - I do.
祂要你保护这些人吗
And he tells you to defend these people?
我走的每一步由祂指引
His hand guides my every step.
这些人是禽兽
These are monsters...
他们无缘无故地灭了整座城镇
who slaughter entire towns without provocation.
屠杀了儿童
Massacre children.
你还为他们祈祷
And you pray for them?
上帝怎么可能跟你这种人说话
How could God speak to you?
我的职责不是质疑
My role is not to question.
而是倾听和侍奉
I listen and serve.
只是听从命令啊
Just following orders, huh?
怎么感觉我在哪里听过这话
Where have I heard that before?
真正的信仰需要怀疑  而我也有我的怀疑
True faith requires doubt and I have mine.
我不会选择暴力之路
Violence is not the path I'd take,
但几个世纪以来  以上帝之名杀戮也很常见
but blood has been spilt in God's name for centuries.
祂的意愿我们无法知晓
His will is unknown to us.
我只能相信祂
All I can do is trust in Him.
上帝不会允许你杀害我的朋友们
God wouldn't allow you to murder my friends
我也不会允许
and neither will I.
让开
Move aside.
你已经听不到祂的声音了  对吗
You don't hear him anymore, do you?
我的信众值得被拯救
My flock is worth saving.
这是你的选择  还是祂的选择
Is that your choice or His?
你现在还倾听吗  好好听
Do you even listen anymore? Listen.
现在祂就在我们身旁
He's here with us right now.
希望你再次听到祂
Asking you to hear him again.
你愿意吗
Will you?
还是说  你要砍倒挡在你面前的神使
Or will you cut down a man that he has placed in your path?
通往和平之路很艰难
The path of peace is hard.
但我们可以一起迈出第一步
But we can take the first steps together.
为了我们的信徒
For both of our flocks.
握住我的手
Take my hand.
重拾你的信仰
Renew your faith.
允许你自己被拯救
Allow yourself to be saved.
不管我们以前做过什么
No matter what any of us have done,
每个人都值得被拯救
no one is above saving.
我可不信
I don't believe that.
糟了
Oops.
转错弯了
Wrong turn.
你杀了我妹妹
You killed my sister.
行吧
Okay.
我必须说声谢谢
Well, I gotta say thanks for this.
正好我找的有点烦了
Was getting tired of all the searching.
这边  混球
Over here, shitdick.
这应该会很有趣
This should be fun.
叮叮
Well, ding-ding.
谢谢  孩子
Thanks, kid.
住手
Stop!
我应该一开始就杀了你
Should've took you out right off.
现在还不能杀他
We don't kill him yet.
他要为自己的行为付出代价
He needs to pay for what he did.
我同意  但如果那样做
I agree. But if we go down that route...
我们就没法全部活着出去了
...we ain't all gonna make it out alive.
无意冒犯
No offense.
我恨这个混蛋
I hate this prick.
但抓到了他就要利用他
But we got him now. Let's use him.
换来想要的东西  然后回家
Get what we want and go home.
你这是为了她吗
Are you doing this for her?
不
No.
不  我是为了我们
No, I'm not. I'm doing it for us.
莉娅想弄死我们  但她更想救家人
Leah wants us gone, but not more than saving her own family.
特别是这个混蛋
Especially this asshole.
这可能会出各种差错
This can go wrong 800 different ways.
但我支持活着出去
Me -- I am down with us getting out of this alive.
-不  -伊莱哲
- No! - Elijah --
你打算就这样放走他吗
You're just gonna let him walk away?
他们会得到报应的
They will get what's coming to them.
也许不是今天  但迟早会的
Maybe not today, but they will.
我保证
I promise.
莉娅  是我
Leah...it's me.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
该死
Shit.
哨声是楼下传来的吧
That whistle came from downstairs, right?
走窗户  去地窖
Use that window. Get to the cellar.
-我们顶着  -好
- We got this. - Okay.
该死  该死
Shit! Shit.
亚伦
Aaron?
-亚伦  -我在里面
- Aaron! - In here!
好  等着  我马上回来
Okay. Hold on. I'll be right back.
好
Sure.
我哪也去不了
I'm not going anywhere.
好了
Okay.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
-谢谢  -嗯
- Thank you. - Yeah.
你也会为我做同样的事
You would've done the same for me.
我会的
I would.
格雷西  朱迪思
Gracie, Judith?
她们很安全
They're safe.
行尸
The walkers --
戴安和罗西塔在处理
Dianne and Rosita, they're on it.
好
Okay.
我们去风车帮忙
Let's go help with the windmill.
好
Okay.
必要时可以丢下我
Leave me here if you have to.
只要确保他死了就行
Just make sure he's dead.
我不会丢下你去任何地方
I'm not going anywhere without you.
不管发生什么
No matter what happens.
好吗
Okay?
准备好了吗
You ready?
嗯
Yeah.
给
Here.
拿着
Take this.
以防万一
Just in case.
莉娅
Leah.
我们在
We're here.
出来
Come out.
武器丢在地上
Throw your weapons on the ground.
我要先看到卡弗
I need to see Carver first!
拿着
Take that.
出来
Come out!
武器丢在地上
Throw your weapons on the ground!
你有什么提议
What are you offering?
放下武器  我们放你们走
Lose the weapons and we let you leave.
就这样吗
Is that all?
你们向北走  别回头
You head north, don't turn back.
我看到任何一个人  都会杀了他
I see anyone, anyone at all, I'm gonna kill him.
等走得够远了  我就放了他
Once we're far out enough, I'll let him go.
-去他的  肖  -闭嘴
- Screw this shit, Shaw. - Shut up.
你指望我现在还相信你吗
You expect me to trust you now?
没错
Yeah. I do.
我们的做法错了
We're doing this all wrong.
我们辛辛苦苦活到现在是为了什么
We survived everything for what?
互相战斗和残杀吗
To keep fighting and killing each other?
如果有必要的话
If that's what it takes.
没必要
Don't have to.
我这是给你机会拯救你的家人
I'm giving you a chance to save what's left of your family.
还有我的家人
And mine.
不能再有更多谎言了
No more lies.
詹森
Jenson.
这是个警告
That was a warning.
最后一次警告
The last one.
所有人都出来
Everybody out!
放低刀  割断绳子
Lower the knife, cut the rope.
詹森  那个女人
Jenson. The woman.
好吧
Fine.
伊莱哲  不要
Elijah, don't.
不许动
No one moves!
伊莱哲
Elijah.
他再走一步就会死
He takes one more step, he dies!
-约瑟芬  -卡弗  不要
- Josephine! - Carve, don't.
停下
Stop.
-詹森  开枪  -她叫约瑟芬
- Jenson, pull the trigger! - Her name was Josephine.
詹森  搞什么鬼
Jenson, what the hell?!
詹森
Jenson!
不
Nope.
詹森不在
No Jenson here.
我是加百利
Call me Gabriel.
另外两人最好退后  不然也会中枪
The other two better back off or they're next.
退下
Stand down.
你的提议还算数吗
Your deal still stand?
你有过机会
You had your chance.
你本会杀死我们
You would've killed us.
一个接一个干掉我们  对吧
Picked us off one by one, right?
现在加百利也会同样对你们
Now Gabriel does the same thing to you.
也许你说得对
Maybe you're right.
枪在你朋友手上
Your friend has the rifle.
但我敢打赌在他杀光我们之前
But I bet we take a couple of you down
我们能带几个人上路
before he takes us all.
镇子还给你
You can have your town.
我们走
We walk.
你救你的家人
You save your family.
我救我的家人
I save mine.
好
Yeah.
尼根
Negan?
我知道我怎么想
You know what I think.
放下武器  离开
Drop your weapons and go.
必须带上卡弗
Not without Carver.
不行
No.
照做
Do it.
我说了照做
I said do it.
我们很快会再见
I'll see you soon.
伊莱哲
Elijah.
为了约瑟芬
For Josephine.
为了所有人
For all of them.
起来
Get up.
玛姬  不
Maggie, no!
这是做什么
The hell was that?!
这不是我想要的结果
This is not what I wanted.
你本可以有第二次机会的
You could've had a second chance.
我们都可以有的
We both could have.
走吧
Go.
在我改变主意之前
Go before I change my mind.
我要走了
I'm gonna head out.
等可以了  我们会赶上你们
We'll catch up with you when we can, okay?
小心点
Be careful.
我很快会回来
I'll be back soon.
我保证
Promise.
奥尔登
Alden!
Alden?
你总是会做你该做的事  玛姬
You were always gonna do what you did, Maggie.
其实我不怪你
I don't blame you really.
但在我这件事上
But, see, when it comes to me...
不管有没有承诺
promise or not...
你迟早都会做出同样的决定
it's just a matter of time before you make the same call.
所以
So...
我不会给你机会那样做
I ain't gonna give you the chance to do that.
我要自己走了
I'm gonna be on my own way.
我听到了你的话
I heard what you said.
我们的做法错了
We're doing it wrong.
我只是想到了选择
I'm just thinking about choices.
现在选择还重要吗
I mean, do they even matter anymore?
这取决于做选择的人是谁
Depends on who's making the choice.
怀疑是很重要的
Doubt's important.
但这不意味着你做错了
But it doesn't make you wrong.
你是要我有信念吗
You telling me to have faith?
嗯  我猜是吧
Yeah, I suppose so, yes.
那你有吗
What about you?
我在努力
Yeah. I'm trying.
I'm trying.
奥尔登
Alden?
见到尼根了吗
You see Negan?
他说他会跟上来
Said he'd catch up.
他走了
He left.
玛姬
Hey, Maggie.
过来
Come on.
没动静吗
All quiet?
其他人呢
Where's everyone else?
达里尔叔叔
Uncle Daryl!
好
Yeah. Ohh.
小家伙
Hey, buddy. Ohh!
-我好想你  妈妈  -我也是  孩子
- Missed you, Mom. - You too, kiddo.
看看你
Look at you.
结束了吗
Is that it?
嗯
Yeah.
-好  -你好
- Yeah. - Hello.
尼根呢
Where's Negan?
他走了
He left.
不会回来了
Ain't coming back here.
给  一人一个
Here you go. Just take one.
你要吗
You want one?
要吗
Want one?
那是所有的食物吗
Is that all food?
我们兑现了承诺
Made a promise and we kept it.
是啊
Yes, you did.
只能拿一个
Yeah, just one, yeah.
不是吧
No way.
很高兴见到你
Happy to see you.
我也是
嗯
Yeah.
要苹果吗
You want an apple?
要吗
Yeah?
我有很多问题想问你
I have so many questions for you.
好吗
Yeah.
我们会修好的
We'll fix it up.
哥们
Hey, man.
你还好吧
You alright?
奥尔登呢
Alden?
他死了
He's gone.
很多人都死了
So many didn't make it.
为了让我们能活下来
All so we could survive.
我们会的
And we will.
暴风雨过后  我们一无所有
After the storm, we had nothing left.
谢谢你
Thank you.
有人来了
Hey! Got something coming!
是你们带来的人吗
These guys with you?
看来不是
Guess not.
所有人  准备好
Everyone get ready!
不不不  等等
No, no, no, no, no. No. Wait.
等等  等等  等等
Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait.
友军
We're all friends.
他们是来帮忙的
They're here to help.
以西结  由美子和我踏上了旅程
Ezekiel, Yumiko, and I set out on a journey.
希望在最黑暗的日子里找到希望
Charged ourselves with finding hope in our darkest of days.
可以说  我们中了头奖
Suffice to say, we hit the proverbial jackpot.
我最好靠边站
It's probably best that I step aside
让你们听本人说吧
so you all can hear it from the horse's mouth as it were.
有请兰斯·霍恩斯比先生
I give you Mr. Lance Hornsby,
联邦外交代表
diplomatic representative of The Commonwealth.
大家好  我是兰斯
Hello. I'm Lance.
感谢允许我们进入你们的家园
Thank you for allowing us into your home.
我必须说  你们建立的东西令我钦佩
I must say I am impressed with everything you've built here
还有我听说的你们的其他社区
and what I've heard of your other communities.
但很显然
But it's clear...
你们陷入了困境
you've fallen on hard times
联邦非常愿意提供帮助
and that is where The Commonwealth is more than willing to help.
如果你们留下  我们可以提供劳力和材料
If you remain, we can provide labor and materials
帮你们重建失去的一切
to help you build back all you've lost.
不过  如果有人感兴趣的话
However, if any are interested...
我还有另一个
I do have another,
可能更有趣的提议
potentially more interesting choice to offer.
六个月后
开门
Open up.
不必这样的
Doesn't have to be this way.
不
Yeah.
必须这样
Yeah, it does.